<NonXMLResume>
  <TextResume>Bryon Trott


    PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

    Bryon Trott has many years experience in the Software industry that include positions as a software test engineer (STE), Software Development in test (SDET) and product support. He has worked with C#, Visual Studio, Powershell, SQL, Product Studio, WTT, Hyper-V and SharePoint while at Microsoft. His work experience at Amazon included testing new software with the Amazon Instant Video Group.  This included creating and running test cases and working with developers to test and close defects.  Bryon has also supported a variety of teams at Microsoft on both an A- and V- basis.  These teams include Xbox Live Publishing, Windows Mobile, Zune MTE, and the connected systems division.  He is also comfortable using Linux, VMware, Ruby, Python, and Java at other companies. Bryon has been acknowledged for developing test cases, streamlining lab procedures, creating technical documentation and training.  Other areas of expertise include operating system installations, network configurations and resolution of system issues.


    SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE


    Microsoft Contract	May 2012 - Nov 2012
    Software Test Engineer Windows Phone 8
    • Software compatibility testing Windows phone applications
    • Created and ran test cases
    • Worked with Developers to test and close defects


    TEKsystems	May 2011 - Feb 2012
    Amazon Contract
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Amazon Cloud computing group
    • Tested new software with the Amazon Instant Video Group.
    • Tested Amazon instant video Application on Android phones and Kindle Fire
    • Created and ran test cases for entire Amazon Instant Video application
    • Used Android tool  and Jira bug tracking software
    • Worked with Developer to test and close defects
    • Bandwidth shaping testing utilized on Linux box.

    Microsoft Contract	April 2010 - April 2011
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Xbox Live Publishing Team
    • Tested new Xbox Game Configuration Tool.
    • Tested Golden Gate web pages and Mastering submission workflow ( This tool is used for moving content to Microsoft Xbox live)
    • Wrote and tested XML based rules
    • Created Test Planning Documents and Test cases
    • Used SQL to verify results on content ingestion (test cases).

    Microsoft Contract	Nov 2009 - Feb 2010
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Windows Mobile phone group LG
    • Ran MTTF tests on LG mobile phones.
    • Created CAB files to put test files on phone using mobile phone CABWIZ

    Microsoft Contract	Jun 2008 -Feb 16, 2009
    Software Developer Engineer in Test SDET
    Microsoft Xbox Online
    • Created Test Plan Documents for Content ingestion in Xbox live
    • Created test cases for Xbox Online Tools that ingested data into the databases.
    • Using Visual Studio team addition.   C# and XML, SQL
    • Used SQL Manager to verify tables and check results.

    Microsoft Contract	Feb 2008 -Jun 16, 2008
    Software Test Engineer SDET
    Microsoft Zune MTE (Mfg Test Environment)
    • Managed specific test areas creating test cases.
    • Ran Manual and Automated Test cases
    • BVT and other tests passes
    • Tested resolved bugs to close
    • Used WTT other test tools

    Digeo Contract	2007 -2008
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Software testing of Moxi Digital Video Recorder and Electronic Program Guide software on Linux based Media Centers.
    • Managed specific test areas on MOXI DVR system.  Thermal, photos  and games
    • Created test plans and test cases for these areas.
    • Ran test cases, tracked and resolved bugs
    • Used Ruby automation, and Linux on MOXI DVR system

    Microsoft Contract	2005 -2007
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Microsoft Connected systems Division
    Contract Test Engineer with CSD group.  Managed automated test cases, resolved issues, scheduled tests, entered bugs, and help requests on system.
    • Created work flow documentation
    • Tested automation software
    • Managed automation computer resources

    Microsoft Contract	2004 -2005
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Microsoft Mouse and Keyboard group
    Contract Test Engineer with Mouse and Keyboard group.  Created test cases and ran test passes, managed application test software and maintained existing test cases.
    • Wrote test specifications, test cases and supporting documents.
    • Held test case review specification meetings.
    • Managed test case tools, test passes and tested bug fixes.

    Microsoft	2000 - 2003
    Software Test Engineer STE
    Windows Division Help and Support Center
    Software Test Engineer supporting Windows Remote Assistance feature in Windows XP   Responsible for running automated and manual test cases and completing test passes for weekly software releases.
    • Managed 50+ Remote Assistance test lab computers and ISP accounts.  Created test configurations and automated operating system installations.
    • Coordinated moving lab to new building with facilities and researched lab needs and requirements.
    • Wrote test specification and test suites for Firewall and Internet Connection Sharing.
    • Administered team's share point portal server.
    • Created CMD Scripts, Jscript and Web pages for testing.

    Microsoft	1993 - 2000
    Software Support Engineer
    Product Support Group (PSS)
    • Software Support in Windows 2000 and Windows CE devices responsible for high volumes of incoming calls and e-mails requesting support.
    • Authored, reviewed and tested articles for the Microsoft knowledge base.
    • Developed and presented training to computer professionals.
    • Created internal support web pages to share team documents.


    Boeing Computer Services	1991 - 1993
    Software Developer
    Programmer/Analyst for Boeing Shop Floor Control Program
    • COBOL software developer on Boeing parts tracking software responsible for maintenance and new programming.  Used COBOL, DB2 and JCL (Job Control Language)
    • Cut nightly job run time by 50% on nightly parts database deletions, by converting program from a serial to parallel process


    EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING
    • University of Washington, Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics
    • Hold VTE 70-321t - Certificate in Software Testing with Microsoft Technologies (06/29/2009)
    • Hold CompTIA A+ and CompTIA Security+ certificates
    • MCAD (Microsoft Certified Application Developer) course at Bellevue Community College
    (VB Script, C#, ASP.NET, T-SQL, XML, HTML, XHTML, CSS)
    • Microsoft Certified Support Engineer (MSCE)
    • CIW (Certified Internet Web) Associate
    • Boeing Computer Services, Business Programming certificate</TextResume>
</NonXMLResume>